DAN T. NGUYEN

(408) 660-7399



HEADLINE -

» I've spent the last five years as an accountant and financial analyst in SaaS Software companies. Having been born and raised in the Silicon Valley, tech has always been a passion of mine, which led to my career in only working at software companies. I made the decision to switch careers and turn a passion into a career from this experience.

EXPERTISE

Web Dev:

- HTML5
- CSS3
- Bootstrap
- Flexbox
- JavaScript
- » JQuery
- » Node.js
- Express.js

- » Angular.js
- React.js
- » React Native
- » MongoDB
- » Firebase
- » Python
- » Git / Github

Software:

- Mac OS / Linux / Windows
- Salesforce
- Netsuite
- » Intacct / Quickbooks
- » Microsoft Office / Google Docs / Quip

PROJECTS -

LaunderThis! Web App

theDanNguyen.com/LaunderWeb

» An export of the LaunderThis! Mobile application as a responsive React web app with firebase

LaunderThis!

theDanNguyen.com/LaunderThis

» A mobile application written in React Native with firebase for export to iOS

Philanthropeas

theDanNguyen.com/philanthropeas

A responsive web application written in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, and MongoDB

EXPERIENCE

Web Development Immersive Student - General Assembly

Austin, TX (Nov 2016 - Present)

» Studying full stack web development languages and frameworks for over 40 hours a week

Revenue and Billing Analyst - Spredfast, Inc

Austin, TX (Nov 2013 - April 2016)

- » Coordinated with Director of FP&A regularly to prepare revenue reporting packages consisting of MRR metrics, variances, ASP, customer and product mix, sales retention, market segmentation, and ad hoc analytics
- Synced multiple financial accounting systems due to data migrations and acquisitions to Salesforce database
- Facilitated quarterly collections of receipts growing from \$4M to \$12M+ to meet forecasted goals
- Owned the sales to collections cycle for company's largest customer accounting for over 5% of total revenue by maintaining a close relationship with our services and sales teams and their business owners
- Managed and reviewed staff accountant's sales orders, invoicing, past due notices, and other GL impacting activities

Staff Accountant - Kinnser Software

Austin, TX (Feb 2012 - Nov 2013)

- Synced Salesforce customer database to Intacct customer database for reporting
- Posted the cash receipts of over 1,000 transactions exceeding \$1M monthly and generated monthly invoices for clients
- Reconciled and managed Sales Tax reporting, filing, and compliance with Avalara Avatax

EDUCATION

University of San Diego (2008 – 2010) Bachelor of Accountancy, Finance Minor